以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
好的，所以我有一些想法
ok so I've got a few things in mind for
今天一个是回答这两个问题
today one is to answer those two
我们回答的第二行问题
questions on the second line we answered
我们发现了这两个公式
the two we found those two formulas on
第一行
the first line
上次反转的导数如此
last time the derivative of a inverse so
平方的导数应该是
the derivative of a squared ought to be
很容易，但如果我们不能这样做，我们需要
easy but if we can't do that we need to
可以肯定，我们可以再这是
be sure we can and then this was the
然后是特征值的导数
derivative of an eigenvalue and then
关于衍生品的问题很自然
it's natural asked about the derivative
奇异的价值，我很高兴
of the singular value and i had a happy
昨天在雪中实现的那一天
day yesterday in the snow realizing that
当然也有一个很好的公式
that has a nice formula too of course
我不是第一个我敢肯定，
I'm not the first I'm sure that
维基百科已经知道这个公式但是
Wikipedia already knows this formula but
这对我来说是新的，我应该说
it was new to me and I should say
阿德尔曼教授把它带到了
professor Adelman has carried it to the
二阶导数再次不是新的，但它是
second derivative again not new but it's
它更难以找到第二
it's more difficult to find second
衍生物和有趣的但会
derivatives and interesting but would
你和第一衍生品一样好吧
you stay with first derivatives okay so
这是我的第一件商品
it's my first item of sort of business
从上次开始，然后我想说
from last time and then I'd like to say
一些有关实验室家庭作业，并要求
something about lab homeworks and ask
你的建议，并开始说些什么
your advice and begin to say something
关于一个项目然后我会搬到
about a project and then I will move to
您在第44节中的这些主题
these topics in section 44 that you have
已经你可能会注意到我跳过了
already and you might notice I skipped
第四0.3，原因在于，上
fourth 0.3 and the reason is that on
周五实际上明天到达麻省理工学院
Friday actually arriving at MIT tomorrow
是Townsend教授
is Professor Townsend
他的特别4.3就是他的工作
whose special 4.3 is all about his work
他是最好的演讲者，我知道他，他
and he's the best lecturer I know he he
做了你知道的8，所以他在这里作为一个
did the 8 you know so he was here as a
指导员并做了1806并且是一个很大的
instructor and did 1806 and was a big
成功
success
实际上他也只是赢了奖
actually he's also just won prize for
ZOA国际奖
the ZOA international prize for the for
年轻的调查员年轻
the for young investigators young
应用线性代数的能力
faculty in applied linear algebra so
他是去香港去做的
he's he goes to Hong Kong to get that
价格无论如何他将在视频上
price to anyway he will be on the videos
如果全部在星期五这里上课
and in here in the class Friday if all
顺利，所以按顺序然后那些
goes well okay so in order then those in
订单第一件事是衍生品
order the first thing is the derivative
一个平方，你可能会认为它是
of a squared and you might think it's to
援助da/dt但它不是，如果你
aid da/dt but it's not and if you
意识到它不是，你意识到
realize that it's not and you realize
你会得到这些东西是什么
what it is you will get these things
就在未来这样的答案
right in the future so the answer to the
平方的导数不是广告
derivative of a squared is not not to ad
一个DT，为什么不是它，它是什么
a DT and why isn't it and what is the
正确答案
right answer
所以我这样做可能只是在这里
so I do that maybe just below here
有没有人清楚，我是问你
did anybody well I could ask you to
猜测正确的答案，但我们为什么不
guess the right answer but why don't we
系统地做，所以你怎么找到
do it systematically so how do you find
衍生品首先是你的限制
the derivative it's a limit first you
有一个delta右边然后你拿一个
have a delta a right and then you take a
限制所以我看一个加上Deltaa
limit so I look at a plus Delta a
平方减去平方所以就是这样
squared minus a squared so that's the
改变一个平方，我用它除以
change in a squared and I divide it by
增量T和然后的ΔT变为0，从而
delta T and then delta T goes to 0 so
那是我正在寻找的衍生物
that's the derivative I'm looking for
平方的衍生物，现在如果我
the derivative of a squared and now if I
写出来，你会看到这是为什么
write that out you'll see why this is
错了但是非常接近它的东西
wrong but something very close to it of
当然离不远就是这样
course can't be far away is right so
如果我把它写出来，会发生什么
what happens if I write this out the a
平方将取消我的平方
squared will cancel the a squared I'll
拥有我将拥有的东西-一个
have what will I have will I have - a
delta我为什么不写-deltaa
delta a why don't I write - a delta a
接下来是因为当你是的时候
next because a because when you're
平均一个矩阵的两个矩阵的总和
squaring a sum of two matrices one term
是deltaa，另一个术语是Deltaa
is a delta a and another term is Delta a
一个和那些在一般和不同
a and those are different in general and
然后加上DeltaVDelta平方和
then Plus Delta V Delta a squared and
现在我将它全部除以deltaT所以你是
now I divide it all by delta T so you're
现在看到我的观点，现在我让DeltaT
now seen my point that now I let Delta T
转到0所以我只是做矩阵
go to 0 so I'm just doing matrix
微积分，你知道它不是
calculus and it's you know it's not
完全简单，但如果你遵循
altogether simple but if you follow the
现在出来的规则是正确的
rules it comes out right so now what
我会得到什么答案，因为deltaT去了
what answer do I get as delta T goes to
0我得到一个DADT这是定义
0 I get a DA DT that's the definition of
该
the
这个比例是da/dt那个
that ratio goes to da/dt that's the
a和a的导数的整体思想
whole idea of the derivative of a and
现在它的另一个术语就是ETA
now what's the other term it's da ETA so
这只是我想要的那一点
it was simply that point that I wanted
你要接受那个衍生品
you to pick up on that da the derivative
可能不会与矩阵通勤
might not commute with a matrices don't
一般通勤，所以你注意到
commute in general and so you notice
我们也有类似的表达中，
that we had a similar expression there
我们必须注意顺序
we had to pay attention to the order of
那里的事情，现在我们做对了
things there and now we get it right
它不是这个，而是daDTplusdaDTa
it's not this but a da DT plus da DT a
好的
okay good
现在，我可以做另一个利基
now can I do the other one niche which
有点严重，但它是一个
is a little more serious but it's it's a
美丽的配方，它是平行的
beautiful formula and it's parallel to
这家伙
this guy
你甚至可能猜到了所以我在寻找
you might even guess it so I'm looking
对于奇异值的导数
for the derivative of a singular value
矩阵a正在改变daDT告诉我
the matrix a is changing da DT tells me
现在它是如何变化的
how it's changing at the moment at the
瞬间，我想知道Sigma是怎样的
instant and I want to know how is Sigma
在同一瞬间改变
changing at that same instant and in
与此并行的是一个很好的
sort of in parallel with this is a nice
D转换daDTV的好公式
D nice formula you transpose da DT V of
你不能要求更好的男孩
T boy you couldn't ask for a nicer
公式，而不是那么正确，所以它只是
formula and than that right so it's just
这样你还记得这是
like this you remember this is the
特征向量，这是特征向量
eigenvector and that's the eigenvector
转置，所以这是单数
of a transpose so this is the singular
矢量的一个，你可以说这是
vector of a and you could say this is
转置的单数向量或
the singular vector of a transpose or
它是一个左边的奇异向量
it's the left singular vector of a so
那将是我们的
that would be our that's our
公式，如果我们可以回忆如何
formula and if we can just recall how to
证明它将是平行的
prove it which is going to be parallel
为证明那个人然后我是一个
to the proof of that one then I'm a
快乐的人，我们可以继续生活
happy person and we can get on with life
好的，所以让我们放手吧
okay so so just let's let's let's
记住这一点，因为它会帮助我们
remember this because it'll help us to
记得另一个太好了，所以在哪里
remember the other one too okay so where
我开始从一个公式开始
do I start I start with a formula for a
西格玛，所以我相信西格玛是你
sigma so I believe that Sigma is U
每个人都转换次数
transpose times a times e everybody
与一切取决于同意
agree with that everything is depending
在这个公式中T作为时间
on T in this in this formula as time
改变一切变化，但我没有
changes everything changes but I didn't
写在圆括号T三三
write in the parentheses T three three
我们可以记得更多次了
more times okay can we just remember
关于SVD，SVD说了一遍
about the SVD the SVD says that a times
V等于保存我，谢谢B是Sigma
V equals save my you thanks a B is Sigma
你这是SVD所以当我投入一个
u that's the SVD so when I put in for a
VI放入SigmauSigma只是一个
V I put in Sigma u Sigma is just a
数字，所以我把它带到外面，我
number so I bring it outside and I'm
左带u转U和什么ü
left with u transpose U and what's u
转移你所以我已经使用了这两个
transpose u what so I've used these two
事实或我本可以走另一条路
facts or I could have gone the other way
并说这是转置的
and said that this is the transpose of
这是一个转置我转置我
this is a transpose u transpose I
不能看着这么认为
couldn't look at it that way
时间V，如果我这样看，我就是
times V and if I look at it that way I'm
感兴趣的是什么是转置U和
interested in what is a transpose U and
什么是转换你的SigmaV和
what is a transpose u its Sigma V and
它的转置使SigmaV转置V和
its transpose so Sigma V transpose V and
什么是SigmaV转换V西格玛
what is Sigma V transpose V its Sigma
当然，西格玛两种方式都可以
again of course got Sigma both ways okay
不，现在我准备好了
no now I'm ready to take
这里是一个的公式我有
here's that's the formula I have for
四西格玛完全平行于
four Sigma completely parallel to the
我们开始用的公式
formula that we started out with for
拉姆达特征值为y转斧
lambda the eigenvalue was y transpose ax
现在我们已经让你转换AV和
and now we've got u transpose AV and by
会是什么时候会这样
the way when would those be
这两个公式是同一个
those two formulas be one and the same
当我们会做的SVD的时候只是
when would we when does the SVD just
告诉我们什么都不是新的
tell us nothing new beyond the
什么是矩阵的特征值
eigenvalue stuff for what matrices are
奇异值与...相同
the singular values the same as the
特征值和看到其他向量
eigenvalues and seeing other vectors the
与此相同，作为for的特征向量
same as this as the eigenvectors for for
对称良好的对称方形和
symmetric good symmetric square and the
我总是在看两个字
two words that i'm them always looking
因为在这个课程中你可以，如果你想
for in this course you could if you want
这个课程中的A只是写下来
an A in this course just write down
肯定的时间和答案
positive definite when and the answer to
任何问题，因为西格玛是由
any question because Sigma's are by
定义是积极的，如果他们要去
definition positive and if they're going
那么完全同意lambdas
to agree totally with the lambdas then
lambdas必须是积极的或可能的
the lambdas have to be positive or could
是0，所以正半正定
be 0 so positive semi definite would be
正确答案这是我们的
the right answer anyway this is our
开始很好，而且我们做什么与
start okay and what do we do with that
公式所以我们这一切都是一样的
formula so so we this was all the same
因为VtransrtV是我在这里的一个
because V transpose V was one here I had
V转置V，这就是它所给出的
V transpose V and that's one so it gave
我是西格玛，是的好
me Sigma yeah good
每个人都用它我做的好做什么
everybody's with it okay what do I do
取导数取
takes the derivative takes the
Box中该方程的导数
derivative of that equation in the Box
正是我上次用的那个
exactly what I did last time with the
lambda的相应方程式相同
corresponding equation for lambda same
事情，我会再次得到它是一个
thing and I'm going to get again it's a
产品规则因为我有三件事
product rule because I have three things
在右侧乘以这样
multiplied on the right hand side so
我从产品中得到了三个术语
I've got three terms from the product
规则所以DSigmaDT来自盒子
rule so D Sigma D T coming from the box
是你转移DtAV是你
is du u transpose D t AV was you
转置daDTV加上第三个人
transpose da DT V plus the third guy
这将是新的转换DVD我做的
which will be new transpose a DVD did I
得到三个术语，是的
get the three terms there yep
我是哪个学期我想要哪个学期
I'm which term do I want which term do I
相信将生存并成为
believe is going to survive and be the
回答这就是我所追求的
answer well this is what I'm after so
这是中期的中期
it's the middle term the middle term is
恰到好处，另外两个术语也有
just right and the other two terms had
最好是零，这样就可以了
better be zero so that that will be the
证明其他两个术语将是
proof the to the other two terms will be
零，所以我们可以采取其中之一
zero so can we just take one of those
两个术语，表明它是零的
two terms and show that it's zero like
这一次还好我有什么我在这里
this one okay what have I got here I
我想知道那个词是零
want to know that that term is zero so
我有什么我有你
what have I got I've got do you
转换DT倍AV和每个人
transpose D T times AV and everybody
在Sigma中代替AV权利说好的
says okay in place of AV right in Sigma
U和Sigma是一个数字所以我不介意
U and Sigma is a number so I don't mind
把它放在那里好，所以我有Sigma
putting it there okay so I've got Sigma
U次的导数的数倍
a number times the derivative of U times
你本身就是衍生品的点积
u itself the dot product the derivative
U与你的点产品和那个
of U with dot product with u and that
等于零我希望因为这个
equals zero I hope because of this
因为我正在接受这个
because of that I'm taking this comes
从那个的衍生物
from the derivative of that the
衍生物将是但但你现在看到了
derivative will be but but you see now
我们有点产品普通点
we've got dot products ordinary dot
产品和右边的数字
products and and a number on the right
手边我们在你的身上
hand side we're in dimension one you
可以这么说，这告诉我
could say so this this tells me
立刻就是U的衍生物
immediately that the derivative of U
与你加你转置时间
with u plus u transpose times the
U的衍生物
derivative of U
是1的导数是0是的
is the derivative of 1 which is 0 yeah
哦，我所说的就是那些
oh all I'm saying is those these are the
同样你知道矢量X转置Y是
same you know vectors X transpose Y is
同样，当我ÿ转X
the same as Y transpose X when I'm
如果我是在谈论实数
talking about real numbers if I was
做我能做的复杂事情
doing complex things which I could do
然后我得注意并采取
then I'd have to pay attention and take
如果和，并采取复杂的共轭
if and and take complex conjugates at
正确的时刻，但不是没有麻烦
the right moment but no it's not bother
所以你看到这只是其中的两个而且
so you see this is just two of these and
它给我0，这样的术语和高尔夫
it gives me 0 so that terms golf and
同样完全相同的这个术语是
similarly totally similarly this term is
走了这是一个转置U但这是什么
gone this is a transpose U but what this
是一个转置你所有的转置我只是
is a transpose u all transpose I'm just
做同样的事情dv/dt和
doing the same thing times dv/dt and
什么是转置你是SigmaV所以
what is a transpose u it's Sigma V so
这是SigmaV转置DVDT和
this is Sigma V transpose DV DT and
再次0因为这样在某种程度上这样
again 0 because of this so in a way this
是一个稍微容易的事情
was a slightly easier thing that the
上次是完全平行的
last time was a completely parallel
计算但第一和第三
computation but the first and third
条款有相互抵消与
terms had to cancel each other with the
X和Y的
X's and Y's
现在他们分开消失了
now they disappear separately leaving
正确答案好吧，你可以
the right answer ok that's you might
想想我们是如何进入衍生品的
think how did we get into derivatives of
奇怪的价值我认为如果我们是
singular values well I think if we're
要了解SVD然后了解
going to understand the SVD then the
Sigma的一阶导数是一个
first derivative of the of Sigma is a
好吧，除了我幸存下来所有这些
well except that I've survived all these
多年没有知道，所以你可以
years without knowing it so you could
说它不是
say it's not
你知道你可以在没有它的情况下生活
you know you can you can live without it
但这是一个非常好的公式好吧
but it's a pretty nice formula okay that
完成3-1和更多部分
completes that sections 3-1 and and more
要说3/2这是
to say about 3/2 which was the
隔行扫描的部分，我介绍好了
interlacing part that I introduced okay
我在哪里
so where am I
我想我正在考虑整洁
I guess I'm thinking about the neat
关于隔行扫描的主题
topics in about interlacing of
特征值所以我可以接受它
eigenvalues so may I pick up on that
似乎是特征值的交织而且说
seem interlacing of eigenvalues and say
笔记中的一般想法是好的
what's in the notes general idea okay so
我们要离开衍生品
we're leaving the leaving derivatives
并转向有限的变化
and moving to finite changes in the
特征值和奇异值我们
eigenvalues and singular values and we
我们认识到我们无法准确
are recognizing that we can't get exact
改变的公式，但我们可以得到
formulas for the change but we can get
改变的边界，他们是
bounds for the change and they are
非常酷，所以让我提醒你什么
pretty cool so let me remind you what
这就是他们所以我有一个
that is what they are so so I have a
矩阵是C对称矩阵S
matrix that's C a symmetric matrix S
具有特征值lambda1更大
that has eigenvalues lambda 1 greater
等于lambda2大于等于那么
equal lambda 2 greater equal so on then
我改变了一些我想到的数量
I change s by some amount I think in the
注意到有一些数字说有时候
notes there's a number say there times a
排名一个具有特征值的矩阵
rank one matrix that has eigenvalues
查看1大于等于mewtwo更大
view 1 greater equal mewtwo greater
等于什么，这就是我
equal something and these are what I
不能给你一个确切的公式为你
can't give you an exact formula for you
只是必须计算它们，但我
just would have to compute them but I
可以给你他们和他们的界限
can give you bounds for them and the
边界来自lambdas所以
bounds come from the lambdas so the
边界是如此，这是积极的
bounds are so this was a positive
这是一个积极的变化所以
this is a positive change so the
特征值会上升或保持不变但是
eigenvalues will go up or stay still but
他们不会失败
they won't go down
所以MUSE会比大
so the muse will be bigger than the
lambda表达式，但整洁的事情是，他们
lambdas but the neat thing is that they
难道你们两个不会放弃lambda1
don't you two will not pass up lambda 1
所以我会在这里静音隔行扫描
so I'll have mute here's the interlacing
NU1是大于或等于1的λ那
nu 1 is greater or equal lambda 1 that
说顶部的最高特征值
says that the highest eigenvalue the top
特征值上升或没有移动但是
eigenvalue went up or didn't move but
但mu2低于lambda1这个新的
but mu 2 is below lambda 1 the new this
这是新来的人和我在一起
is the new everybody's with me here this
是新的，这是旧的和新的
is the new and this is the old new and
老是最古老的snu随着变化
old being oldest s nu is with the change
在s和mu2更大相等
in s and that mu 2 is greater equal
lambda2所以第二个特征值去了
lambda 2 so the second eigen values went
那就是那个就是那个
up and then so on that's the that's the
很棒的事实，我想我发了一个
great fact and I guess that I sent out a
难题问题是否确实到了
puzzle question did did it arrive in
关于假设的电子邮件
email about suppose so
有没有人看到这个谜题
does anybody see that puzzle question
并考虑一下
and think about it
所以这让我担心了一段时间
so here's it worried me for a while
假设这个改变，因为它假设我
suppose this change as it is suppose I'm
在这里添加假设这是
adding on here suppose this is the
第二个特征值特征向量所以我
second eigenvalue eigenvector so i'm
加上我正在加剧第二次
adding on i'm hyping up the second
特征向量增加了矩阵
eigenvector hyping up the matrix in the
所述第二本征向量的方向，从而
direction of the second eigenvector so
我真的是第二个特征值
i'm really so the second eigenvalue was
lambda2和它的美丽是新的第二个
lambda 2 and it's beauty the new second
特征值将会更大
eigenvalue is going to be bigger by
theta然后我失去了一点
theta but this then i lost a little
睡觉时思考还行，如果第二个
sleep in thinking okay if the second
特征值是mu2
eigenvalue is mu 2
再加上theta我很抱歉，如果第二个
Plus theta I'm sorry if the second
特征值mewtwo所以让我写出来
eigenvalue mewtwo so so let me write it
这里
here
如果mu2第二个特征值是旧的
if mu2 the second eigenvalue is the old
lambda2加上theta然后然后
lambda 2 plus theta then then then then
坏消息因为theta可以像
bad news because theta can be as big as
我希望它可以是2200毫米，当我，如果
I want it can be 2200 mm and when I if
如果我只是添加theta2，这个mu2
this mu 2 if I'm just adding theta 2 to
lambda2得到那个，因为它是
lambda 2 to get that second because it's
那是第二个特征向量
the second eigenvector that that's
过了一会儿就抽了一下
getting pumped up then after a while
亩TOU将通过拉姆达1，这将是
mu tou will pass lambda 1 this will be
完全正确我不愁
totally true I have no worries about
这个老lambda1实际上是旧的
this the old lambda 1 actually the old
旧的我甚至可以有平等这里
the old I'll even have equality here
因为这个特殊的变化是
because for this particular change it's
不影响lambda1所以我认为mu1
not affecting lambda 1 so I think mu 1
在我的假设中会是lambda1in
would be lambda 1 in in my hypothetical
我试图找到你的可能性
possibility where I'm trying to get you
要做的就是思考一下这个
to do is to think through what this
意思是因为写起来很容易
means because it's quite easy to write
那条线，但那时你想
that line there but then when you think
关于它你得到一些问题和它
about it you get some questions and it
它看起来好像可能会失败
looks 10 it looks as if it might fail
是的，因为如果theta真的很大
right because if theta is really big
那个Mew2会传递lambda1和
that Mew 2 would pass up lambda 1 and
事情会失败，必须有
the thing would fail and there has to be
捕获它必须是一个捕获所以
a catch it has to be a catch so does
你在电子邮件中看到的任何人
anybody Minh you saw that in the email
我现在要解释一下我的情况
and I'll now explain what I how I
明白了那一切
understood that the ever that everything
可以工作，而不是我不在的地方
can work and there isn't where I'm not
达成矛盾，这是我的
reaching a contradiction and here's my
思维
thinking
所以这完全正确
so it's perfectly true that the
与你同在的特征值-或者也许
eigenvalue that goes with you - or maybe
我应该称他们为X-因为
I should be calling them X - because
通常我称之为特征向量x2
usually I call the eigenvectors x2 it's
完全正确的那个mu-那一个
perfectly true that mu - that that one
上升但是当它击中时会发生什么
goes up but what happens when it hits
当它达到λ1实际上是lambda
when it reaches lambda 1 actually lambda
1第一个特征值是保持不变
1 the first eigenvalue is staying put
因为它没有得到任何推动
because it's not getting any push from
这个但第二个特征值是
this but the second eigenvalue is
如此推动大小theta
getting a push of size theta so so what
当lambda2加上静音时发生
happens when mute when lambda 2 plus
mu2u2的theta是lambda2plus
theta which is mu 2 u 2 is lambda 2 plus
theta什么时候会发生什么
theta what happens when it comes up to
lambda1和我开始担心它
lambda 1 and I start worrying that it
通过lambda1你会看到发生了什么
passes lambda 1 you see what's happening
当mu2通过时会发生什么
there what happens when mu 2 passes when
mu2这是我要复制的
mu 2 which is I'm just going to copy
这里是旧的lambda2加上相同的
here it's the old lambda 2 plus the same
作为一个数字，当theta得到时会发生什么
as a number what happens when theta gets
越来越大，这个
bigger and bigger and bigger and this
打这个东西，然后超越
hits this thing and then goes beyond
只是为了看到这里发生的逻辑
just to see the logic here what happens
是这个lambda2加上theta哪个
is that this lambda 2 plus theta which
是2亩2，直到他们到了这里
was mu 2 mu 2 until they've got here but
什么是lambda2加上theta之后
what is lambda 2 plus theta after it
现在它将lambda1传递给lambda1
passes lambda 1 its lambda 1 now it
这是它的最高特征值
passed up so it's the top eigenvalue of
改变的矩阵和
the of the of the altered matrix and
因此它就好了，就在这里
therefore it's just fine it's out here
没问题，是的
no problem yeah
或许我会再当时说
maybe I'll just say it again when when
theta足够大，mu2到达
theta is big enough that mu 2 reaches
lambda1如果我增加theta超过那个
lambda 1 if I increase theta beyond that
那么这不再是mu2了，但是你
then this becomes not mu 2 anymore but u
1然后完全让每个人都开心
1 and then totally everybody's happy
好吧，我只是不会就此而言
okay I'll just I won't say more on that
因为那只是像一个办法
because that's just like a way for that
我发现让我沉溺于这些
I found to make me sink what do these
事情的意思还可以
things mean okay enough said on that
小点，但接下来的主要观点是
small point but then the main point is
为什么这是真的
why is this true
这是隔行扫描，真的很棒
it's interlacing which is really a nice
美丽的事实，你可以想象
beautiful fact and you could imagine
我们有更多不同
that we have more different
扰动而不仅仅是排序
perturbations than just rank ones so
假设是的，所以让我告诉你
suppose yeah so so let me tell you the
以他们命名的不平等
the inequality so named after they
发现小瓶不平等所以他的
discover vials inequality so his
不等式是s的特征值
inequality is for the eigenvalues of s
加上T和我想啊所以T是
plus T and I want to yeah so T is the
改变S，我开始有
change s is where I start it has
特征值lambda但现在我正在寻找
eigenvalues lambda but now I'm looking
在S加特征的特征值所以我是
at the eigenvalues of s plus T so so I'm
在这里和我的改变
making a change in over here and my
这是十几岁的小它谜题
little puzzle question that was teens it
现在我可以允许，这是一个排名改变
was a rank one change now I could allow
其他等级还行，所以我想估计一下
other ranks okay so I want to estimate
就lambda而言，s加上t的lambda
lambdas of s plus T in terms of lambdas
T和我的lambdas和我想要一些
of s and lambdas of T and I want some
那里的不平等标志和它的假设
inequality sign there and it's supposed
对于任何对称矩阵都是如此
to be true for any symmetric matrices
对称smt然后完全完全
symmetric smt and then a totally totally
相同的小提琴平等实际上是viol
identical violin equality actually viol
是发现的人之一
was one of the people who discovered
看到欧拉的价值观，当他做到了
seen Euler values and when he did it he
询问他的不平等，他发现了
asked about his inequality and he found
它仍然按照我们发现的方式工作
that it still worked the way we found
今天早上它说了什么
this morning earlier that it said what
我不知道我还没完成
I'm what I haven't I haven't completed
那是因为我没有告诉你
that yet because I haven't told you
我正在谈论哪些lambdas
which lambdas I'm talking about
对，所以让我这样做，现在告诉你
right so let me do that so now tell your
文件不等，所以S＆T或对称和
files inequality so S&T or symmetric and
所以lambdas是真实的，我们想要
so the lambdas are real and we want to
我们知道我们想让他们整理好
know we want to get them in order okay
所以在这里
so here it goes
我要到这里来，我要提交
I'm going to over here I'm gonna file
大声朗读了s的冰特征值
aloud the ice eigenvalue of s and the
吨的JSON值，并计算出该
json value of t and figured out that
这是由S的特征值建立的
this was founded by that eigenvalue of S
加上T这是最糟糕的不平等
Plus T so that's vilest great inequality
这减少到我写的那个
which reduces to the the the one I wrote
在这里如果我做出正确的选择是的
here if I make the right choice yeah
可能如果我把J等于一等那么
probably if I take J equal to one so so
这是你看到它的美丽
this was you see the beauty of this it
告诉你有关的所有任何特征值
tells you about all any eigen values of
T的特征值所以我使用lambdas
s eigen values of T so I'm using lambdas
这里S的拉姆达是的特征值
here lambda of s are the eigenvalues of
我再次使用lambda作为T和
s I'm using lambda again for T and
lambda再次为s加T所以就是这样
lambda again for s plus T so it's that
你要注意哪个
you have to pay attention to which
矩阵我走的如此的特征值
matrix I'm taking the eigen values of so
让我把J等于一个然后这个
let me take J equal to one then this
说lambdaI因为J是1s加
says that lambda I because J is 1 s plus
T加R等于s的lambdaI加上lambda
T plus R equal lambda I of s plus lambda
1这是T的顶部本征值
1 the top eigen value of T this is
lambdamaxofT.
lambda max of T
你看到那是完全的吗？
do you see that that's totally
合理可信的
reasonable believable that the
当我加上Tlet时的特征值
eigenvalues when I add on T let's
在我们的脑海中想象T是积极的
imagine in our minds that T is positive
T是T就是这样这件事情，这是
T is T is like this this thing this is
这可能是茶的T例子
the this could be the T example of a tea
这就是我正在添加的内容
it's what I'm adding on then the
特征值上升但它们没有通过
eigenvalues go up but they don't pass
这样就可以告诉你它能做多少
that so that tells you how much it could
上升，所以我猜我猜
go up by so I guess that I guess that
小瓶告诉我们给了我们更少
vial is telling us is giving us a less
或者等于或小于lambda1
or equal here less or equal to lambda1
所以我带我去1加theta耶
so I'm taking I to be 1 plus theta yeah
是啊
yeah
所以我写下了不平等
so that inequality I've written down
那里有一些游戏要做
there there's some playing around to do
所以要练习并不是这样
so to get practice and it's not so
我们必须像世界一样
essential for us to be like world
除了你，这件事的大师们
grandmasters at this thing but you
应该看到它，你也应该看到J.
should see it and you should also see J
等于2y将J等于2告诉我们
equal to 2y will J equal to 2 tell us
我希望它会让我们看到什么
something I hope it will let's see what
它告诉我们lambdaI加1现在J是2
it tells us lambda I plus 1 now J is 2
小号加t，因此它是一个小于或
of S Plus T so it's a is less than or
等于λ的s加上TI的lambda2
equal lambda I of s plus lambda 2 of T I
认为这很有趣，或者也是
think that's interesting or and and also
我可以接受，我想我也可以得到
I could take I think I also could get
lambdaI加上我减1，所以这些让我
lambda I plus I minus 1 so these let me
写下来，看看它是否正确加
write it and see if it's correct plus
lambda我减1，所以加起来
lambda I minus 1 so that was added up to
我加2是啊我猜lambda加1
I plus 2 yeah I guess lambda I plus 1
再加上lambda的一颗牙齿
plus lambda one of teeth
是啊，这就是我通过采取做呀
yeah that's what I got by taking yeah do
那是对的，我把J等于一
that right I'm taking J equal to one
哦，我不认为我得到了它
oh well did I I don't think I got it
对，我想在这里做什么
right what am what do I want to do here
得到一个关于lambdaI加一个我的约束
to get a bound on lambda I plus one I
我想把J等于2我应该
want to take J equal to 2 I should just
要明智并插入等于2和我
be sensible and plug in a equals 2 and I
所有我想说的就是viols
equal 1 all I want to say is that viols
不平等是伟大的事实出来的
inequality is the great fact out of
所有这些交织的瀑布和
which all this interlacing Falls and
越来越多，因为隔行扫描是
more and more because the interlacing is
告诉我有关邻居的事实
telling me about neighbors and actually
如果我使用卑鄙的和我和J
if I use vile for a and I and J
不同的眼睛和J我甚至学习
different eyes and J's I even learn
关于那些不是邻居但是
about ones that are not neighbors but
我可以告诉你一个Vile的证据
and I could tell you a proof of Vile's
不平等，但我会为此保存
inequality but I'll save that for the
注意是的好，所以我想也许就是这样
notes yes okay so I think maybe that's
关于隔行扫描我想做什么
what I want to do about interlacing just
只是说说什么，但没有
just to say what the notes have but not
在课堂上重复这一切，所以笔记有
repeat it all in class so the notes have
实际上有两种方法来证明这一点
actually two ways to prove this
隔行扫描每一个标准的方式
interlacing the standard way that every
数学家会使用Vile的
mathematician would use would be Vile's
不平等，但亲爱的教授饶
inequality but less dear professor Rao
来访发现了一个不错的论点
visiting found a nice argument that's
它也以音符结尾
also in the notes it ends up with a
图和上图可以看出，
graph and on that graph you can see that
这是真的，所以它值得两个
this is true so for what it's worth two
这种隔行扫描的方法
approaches to this to this interlacing
和一些例子，但我真的没有
and some examples but I really don't
想花
want to spend
我们的生活在那个直升机上
our lives on that chopper this
特征值主题它是一个美丽的
eigenvalue topic it's it's a beautiful
关于对称矩阵和对偶矩阵的事实
fact about symmetric matrices and the
相应的事实是真实的
the corresponding fact is true for
任何矩阵的奇异值，但让我们
singular values of any matrix but let's
我想现在就把它留在那里好吧
I think of leaving it there okay so now
我正在继续他们新的部分
I'm moving on to their new section the
新节涉及一些事情
new section involves something called
压缩传感我不知道是否
compressed sensing I don't know if
你已经听过这些话了
you've heard those words so these are
您在第4.4节中的所有主题
all topics in Section 4.4 which you have
从我认为我们送出来十天前
from I think we send it out ten days ago
可能没关系所以首先让我记住
probably okay so first let me remember
什么核标准是一个矩阵的
what the nuclear norm is of a matrix the
矩阵的核范数的总和
nuclear norm of a matrix is the sum of
奇异值有一些
the singular values there's some of the
奇异值，所以它就像l1规范
singular values so it's like the l1 norm
对于一个正确的思考方式的向量
for a vector that's a right way to think
关于它，你还记得那是什么
about it and do you remember what was
我们特别谈到了使用方法
special we we've talked about the using
l1规范它有这个特殊的特殊性
the l1 norm it has this special special
普通l2规范的财产
property that the ordinary l2 norm
绝对没有它是什么
absolutely does not have what was it
如果我这么特别关于地狱的常态
special about the hell one norm if I
尽量减少一些尽量减少与l1范
minimize some minimize the l1 norm with
E有一些约束，比如axaV等于
E with some constraint like ax a V equal
B解决方案有什么特别之处
B what's special about the solution the
最小的l1范数稀疏权利
minimum in the l1 norm sparse right
稀疏，所以这让我们两个
sparse so this is moving us up two
矩阵和压缩的地方
matrices and that's where compressed
传感来自矩阵
sensing comes in matrix come
利森进来这里矩阵
Leeson comes in so here matrix
完成只是我提到的
completion would just be I mentioned so
这是完成，我会记住
this is completion and I'll remember the
Netflix这个问题就出现了
words Netflix which made the problem
着名，所以我有矩阵3-2
famous so I have the matrix a 3-2
问号问号
question mark question mark question
标记一个四个问题一个丢失
mark one four six question one missing
数据，所以我必须投入一些东西
data and so I have to put in something
因为如果我没有投入任何东西
there because if I don't put in anything
然后我不知道的数字是
then the numbers I have dunno are
没用，因为我不知道排和不
useless as I can't know row and no
列已完成，所以我们只是给
column is complete so we just would give
有人给我发了三个数据
up somebody that sent me the data three
和两个并没有出售告诉我一个
and two and didn't sell tell me a
我必须排名第三部电影
ranking for the third movie I'd have to
说得好我不能用它
say well I can't use it
这是不可能的，所以我们需要思考
that's not possible so we need to think
关于那里和想法是
about there and the idea is that the
最小化核规范的数字
numbers that minimize the nuclear norm
是一个不错的选择不错的选择等等
are a good choice a good choice so
这只是一个连接在这里，我们将
that's just a connection here that we'll
多谈谈，但不是没有，我们可以有
say more about but not not we could have
整个过程压缩传感a
a whole course compressed sensing a
核规范
nuclear norm
Perillo教授当然还有
professor Perillo and and of course in
当然六个六等于这方面的专家
six of course six is an expert on this
但问题是，你看到的点
but the point is you see the point that
那么你还记得什么是VV
so what is the you remember V V one came
从零北
from the zero north
什么是向量的零范数
and what is the zero norm of a vector
好吧，这不是一个常态，所以你可以说
well it's not a norm so you could say
忘记它不是没有答案，但我们做什么
forget it no no answer but what do we
象征意味着我写零
symbolically mean when I write the zero
向量的范数我的意思是数量
norm of a vector I mean the number of
非零非零的数量
non-zeros the number of non-zeros
这是非零的数量
this was the number of non zero in the
主要事件，但它不是一个常态，因为
main event but it's not a norm because
如果我拿两次我的矢量
if I take two times the vector I have
相同数量的非零相同的规范我
the same number of non-zeros same norm I
不能有两个V等于的标准
can't have the norm of two V equal to
电子商务的规范，即，这将吹走
norm of e that that that would blow away
规范的所有属性，所以V为零
all the properties of norms so V zero is
不是常态，我们把它移到那种
not a norm and we move it to the sort of
适当的最接近的标准，我们得到V1
appropriate nearest norm and we get V 1
我们得到L1范数，它是和的总和
we get the L 1 norm which is the sum of
每个人都记得这就是
the everybody remembers that this is the
V的总和，你记得我的
sum of the V on and you remember my
钻石触及飞机的图片
pictures of diamonds touching planes at
尖锐的是，这是正在发生的事情
sharp point well that's what's going on
这里的问题被称为基础
here that problem was called basis
追求又回来了
pursuit and comes back again in this
部分确定，但所以我最小化这个规范
section ok but so I minimize this norm
受条件限制好了我现在
subject to the conditions okay now I'm
只是要采取跳转到矩阵
just going to take a jump to the matrix
案件我的想法在这里我的想法是什么
case what's my idea here my idea is that
核规范的矩阵来了
the for matrix the nuclear norm comes
从什么是我们排序的标准
from what what's the norm that we sort
一开始，但这不是常态
of start with but it's not a norm and
当我有点像我那样
when I sort of take the I sort of
因为三角不等式或
because of triangle inequality or the
对规范的要求不会让他们失望
requirements for a norm don't fail they
失败了
fail for what
我准备在那里写我可以放一个
I'm about to write there I could put a
零，但我不希望数量
zero but I don't want the number of
非零的条目，这将是一个很好的
nonzero entries that would be a good
猜测，可能在某种意义上说它
guess and probably in some sense it make
它是有道理的，但它不是答案
it make sense but it's not the answer
我在找
I'm looking for
你认为什么是零的标准？
what do you think is the zero norm of a
矩阵，这不是一个规范，但何时
matrix that that is not a norm but when
我把它抽到最近的地方
I pump it up to the best to the nearest
好的规范我按顺序获得核
good norm I get the nuclear in order so
所以这就是问题是什么
so this is the question is what is a
零是什么级别的军衔
zero what the rank the rank of the
矩阵是等效是在IS
matrix is is the equivalent is the is
这是我不知道的
the is the so I don't know about the
零没有人要求在零，所以我
zero nobody else calls at a zero so I
更好的不是它的排名所以再次
better not it's the rank so again the
排名不是常态，因为如果我加倍
rank is not a norm because if I double
矩阵我没有加倍排名但是
the matrix I don't double the rank but
如果是的话我要搬到一个规范，它
if so I have to move to a norm and it
结果证明是现在的核规范
turns out to be the nuclear norm and now
我只想一分钟说这是猜测
I'll just one minute say it's the guess
有些人正在努力工作
of some people who are working hard to
证明这是深刻的学习
prove it that the deep learning
梯度下降算法找到了
algorithm of gradient descent finds the
溶液在最小问题
solution to the minimum problem in the
核规范，我不知道
nuclear norm and I don't we don't know
如果那是真的
if that's true or not
是的，我们是第一个小相关的
yeah we're first small for for related
像这样的东西它被证明是例子
examples like this thing it's proved for
这是深度学习的确切问题
the exact problem of deep learning it's
这是一个猜想没关系
it's a conjecture okay
所以这是在四四节
so that's what's in Section four four
但是你想要的那个单词套索
but other that word lasso you want to
知道什么是压缩传感
know what that is compressed sensing
我会说一个关于这样的话
I'll say a word about so that will be
AlexTownsend演讲结束后的星期一
Monday after Alex Townsend's lecture
星期五所以他要来发言了
Friday so he's he's coming to speak
-计算科学专业的学生
- computational science students all
麻省理工学院明天下午我会
over MIT tomorrow afternoon I'll
当然可以去那，但他说他
certainly go to that but then he said he
会进来，并借此类星期五
would come in and take this class Friday
so I'll see you Friday
所以我星期五见
他会在这里-好的
and he'll be here - okay